# Francois Naude (BEng Computer)

### **Contact Details**

Mobile No: +27716749057E-mail: mail@bfjnaude.com

# **Personal Summary**

A highly efficient and versatile engineering professional, with demonstrated expertise in systems design and implementation. Specialises in problem solving on multiple levels, while maintaining awareness of system wide implications. Built and maintained a reputation of integrity, exceptional work quality and an open approach to design solutions. A go to person for technical recommendations.

#### **Skills**

- Strong analytical and problem solving skills
- Prioritising multiple responsibilities, without compromising on work quality
- Confident working with large code bases and on multiple platforms
- Proven ability to quickly grasp and apply new technologies or 3rd party APIs
- Strong communication skills of technical ideas to both technical and non technical colleagues
- Build and maintain physical and virtual computer networks

# **Tools & Technologies**

- C, C++ and Lua for Windows (5 years)
- Microsoft Visual Studio (5 years)
- Server administration in Windows and Linux (5 years)
- Golang (1+ year)
- HTML, JS & CSS (1+ year)
- ReactJS (1+ year)
- Postgresql (1+ year)
- Amazon Web Services (1+ year)
  - Cloudformation for resource deployment
  - IAM & Cognito for user authentication and authorization
  - Lamda, Elastics Cloud Compute and Elastic Container Service for running functions and containers
  - API Gateway for RESTfull API hosting
  - S3 & Cloudfront for website hosting

# **Employment**

November 2019 - Present:

Senior Developer at TrueVolve Technologies working on legacy system maintenance and feature development of Linux-based C++/Golang services.

#### Responsibilities

- Finding and fixing bugs in legacy C++ code
- Designing and adding new features to existing APIs in C++ and Golang
- Updating protocol documenation
- RESTful Web API design

April 2018 - October 2019:

Developer at uAfrica.com working on a microservice based software as a service platform for courier logistics.

#### Responsibilities

- Microservice design and implementation in Golang
- RESTful Web API design
- Designing and maintaining scalable infrastructure on AWS with servers and serverless
- Implementing frontend for microservice platform using ReactJS and Bootstrap CSS

January 2013 - March 2018:

Computer Engineer at Fifth Dimension Technologies (5DT) working on virtual reality training simulators in C/C++ and Lua for Windows.

#### Responsibilities

- SDK development in C/C++
- Legacy code maintenance in C/C++
- Finding and fixing bugs in production
- Product development in Lua and C/C++
- Product management: drafting specifications and test procedure documents, cooperating with production teams, ensuring that deadlines are met
- Documentation of codebases
- Product quality assurance
- Internal tool development: Helper applications for support teams, diagnostic applications for in-house hardware
- Network, server and account administrator (Linux & Windows)Can communicate technical ideas and details effectively

# **Education**

- Bachelor Degree in Computer Engineering (BEng Computer Cum Laude) from the University of Pretoria (2009 2012)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate 1 to 4 from the University of Pretoria (2009-2010)
- Cisco Certified Network Professional 1 (2011)

# **Achievements**

- Consistently exceeding performance measures, demonstrated through performance reviews and stakeholder feedback
- Academic honorary colours from University of Pretoria (2012)
- Silver Wilhelm Leuschner Prize for academic achievement in Computer Engineering from University of Pretoria (2012)
- Awarded best third year computer engineering project from University of Pretoria (2011)
- Silver merit for academic achievement in computer engineering from University of Pretoria (2011)